<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>audio.dusk.studio</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Dusk Studio</name>
  <summary>Portastudio-style 24-channel DAW</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Dusk Studio is a deliberately constrained, portastudio-style digital audio
      workstation. Fixed 24-channel topology with a fixed signal chain
      (HPF, 4-band EQ, FET/Opto compressor, sends, pan, mute/solo,
      fader), four aux buses, and a mastering chain with passive program EQ,
      bus compressor, tape saturation, and limiter.
    </p>
    <p>
      Built for musicians who want to commit to sounds and finish songs
      instead of endlessly tweaking. Inspired by Tascam Portastudio
      hardware: every parameter is visible, no plugin chains, no
      bus reordering, no waveform-level editing.
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">audio.dusk.studio.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>DuskStudio</binary>
    <mediatype>application/x-dusk-studio-session</mediatype>
  </provides>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/dusk-audio/dusk-studio</url>
  <developer_name>Dusk Audio</developer_name>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <!-- scripts/bump-version.sh prepends new <release> entries here. -->
    <release version="0.12.4" date="2026-07-18">
      <description>
        <p>Filterable program-grouped SoundFont preset browser.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.3" date="2026-07-15">
      <description>
        <p>Input monitoring now feeds aux sends during playback.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.2" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Beta patch: fixes a mixdown/stems/freeze crash with CLAP (and VST3/LV2) plugin inserts.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.1" date="2026-07-12">
      <description>
        <p>Beta patch: live play-along during playback, Mackie fader calibration, Windows plugin-scan sandbox fix, deterministic bounces.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.12.0" date="2026-07-11">
      <description>
        <p>Beta. Workflow: session sample-rate policy, seamless loop playback,
        Save As consolidation, aux return latency compensation, MIDI soft
        takeover, LV2 file state in sessions, delivery presets, and background
        audio imports. Sound: the console EQ on every channel and bus moves to
        a new-generation core with a subtle re-voicing, and the channel EQ and
        compressor path is lighter on the CPU. Launching on Wayland without
        XWayland now shows a clear message explaining how to enable it instead
        of crashing, and the MIDI engine internals have been modernised.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.1" date="2026-06-24">
      <description>
        <p>Patch release on the 0.11 Beta line. Chase / follow playhead in the
        timeline and editors, a bar / beat grid in the audio and MIDI editors,
        a reworked top-row layout with the stage selector in the menu row, and a
        keyboard-shortcut cleanup. Fixes a startup hang when the saved audio
        device is busy (falls back to another device with a notice) and an ALSA
        crash on interfaces with fewer than 32 channels. Adds a Raspberry Pi
        (arm64) Linux tarball.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.11.0" date="2026-06-12">
      <description>
        <p>Beta release. Optional out-of-process plugin sandbox with
        crash-isolated plugin scanning on all three OSes,
        automatic cross-track plugin delay compensation,
        broad undo coverage (notes, automation, tempo, renames), tempo
        editing from the ruler, portable session folders, MIDI Learn for
        EQ frequency/Q, multi-output cue routing, true-peak mastering
        limiter, and a data-integrity and real-time-safety hardening
        pass (atomic session save, autosave recovery, MIDI-out xruns,
        crash fixes on stop and quit).</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.10.0" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>First beta. MIDI binding targets across the mixer, screen-reader
        accessibility for the channel strips, audio-device hot-unplug
        recovery, macOS out-of-process plugin pipeline with in-process
        editors, and Linux arm64 builds.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.9.0" date="2026-05-21">
      <description>
        <p>Beta release leading up to 1.0. Phase 4 MIDI tempo retime,
        BPM-change confirmation dialog, 64-sample raised-cosine punch
        crossfade, triplet quantize variants, and packaging targets
        for Linux AppImage / deb / rpm, Windows MSI, macOS DMG.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
